profileengine.com 2015-03-17

# Privacy policy : The Profile Engine

Profile Technology Ltd privacy policy 2011

**PRIVACY POLICY**

Profile Technology Limited create and develop a range of websites and social network applications. Within this document the term 'Sites' shall refer to any and all of our applications, websites and any other services we provide. Where we collect personally identifiable information from you ("Personal Information") we will deal with that information in accordance with our Terms of Service and the _Privacy Policy_ set out below.

**Privacy Policy**

The Privacy Policy sets out the basis on which we will deal with any Personal Information we collect from you, or that you provide to us. We have adopted our Privacy Policy so that our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your Personal Information complies with the Privacy Act 1993. By using our Sites, you agree to this Privacy Policy.

Solely for the purpose of this Privacy Policy "we", "us", or "our" means Profile Technology Limited and/or MrMr C L aydon. 

**Information we may collect from you**

We may collect and process the following information about you:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Sites. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use Sites, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with any of our Sites.

  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

  * We may ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.

  * Details of your use of our Sites including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data and other communication data and logs of the resources that you access.

  * Any other information which you submit to othe social networks and which is made available by those social networks for use by Platform Developers in accordance with their policies. 'API data'

  * Any parts of your profile on another social network which that social network has allowed our search engine to download and store at a time when your privacy settings permitted search engines to index those parts of your profile. Note that such information is not obtained via the "Platform APIs" and therefore our use of this information is not controlled by the developer policies of the social network Developer Policy. Information collected in this way is treated by us as "Public information". _Note: We are not notified if you revoke the permission for search engines to index your profile and doing so will not remove your profile from our database. Revoking that permission only prevents search engines from accessing changes make to your profile after you revoked the permission._

**IP addresses and cookies**

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type. Please note that we may use geolocation software which may identify your IP address as belonging to a particular area. This is not 100% accurate but may lead to the disclosure of the region from which you access our Sites. By accessing our Sites you agree to the public disclosure of this information.

We may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our Sites and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us:

  * To log you in to the Sites and keep your login session active.

  * To estimate our audience size and usage pattern.

  * To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise Sites according to your individual interests.

  * To speed up your searches.

  * To recognise you when you return to Sites. 

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Sites or they may not work correctly. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system may issue cookies whenever you use our Sites.

**Where we store your personal data**

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination within or outside New Zealand. It may be processed by staff who work for us or for one of our suppliers or contractors anywhere in the world. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of technical or support services. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing and processing.

All information you provide to us may be stored on our servers. Any payment transactions will be dealt with by PayPal or another payment processor of our choice in accordance with their terms. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password or other secure login method which enables you to access certain parts of our Sites, you are responsible for keeping this password or secure login method confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not necessarily secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of information about you when it is transmitted to and from our Sites; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

We regularly backup information and data that we hold to improve the integrity of our Sites in the event of a system failure. Please note that these backups may be stored indefinitely and will hold a snapshot of the information we held about you at that time. Therefore, any changes that you make to the information you supplied to us after the date of the backup will not change the information contained in that backup.

Where it is necessary to restore data or build a new database from a backup copy, recent changes may be lost and old or deleted content may reappear on the system. We may attempt to alert you to this fact where it is deemed necessary and you have provided contact information but we are under no obligation to do so. It is up to you to check regularly and ensure your details are up to date. 

**Use of your information**

We may use your Personal Information in the following ways:

  * To be used in conjunction with any of our Sites.

  * To enable other users of our Sites to find you, identify you, learn about you and contact you.

  * To ensure that content from our Sites is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 

  * To provide you with information, products, or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you.

  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.

  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.

  * To notify you about changes to our service.

  * For any other purpose related to, or arising from, the above purposes.

If you do not want us to use your information in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for these purposes, please do not **** tick the relevant box or do not provide your email address or other personal information on the form on which we collect your information (the “Registration Form”).

We may also use your information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target. We may make use of the Personal Information we collect from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to you.

**Disclosure of your information**

You agree that your information can be shared between our Sites and passed to any of our related companies which means we may disclose your Personal Information to (without limitation) our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries.

We may disclose any Personal Information you provide us to any third parties for any purpose, including (without limitation):

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your Personal Information to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets and they will be able to use such information in accordance with the Terms.

  * If disclosure is required for the ordinary operation of the Sites, our business, or any third party’s.

  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your Personal Information in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**Your rights**

You have the right to ask us not to process your Personal Information for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your Personal Information) if we intend to use your Personal Information for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your Personal Information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your Personal Information. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us directly or by using the unsubscribe link on marketing e-mails we have sent to you.

Our Sites may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**Your Access to your Personal Information**

If we hold Personal Information about you, you may request access for amendments to or deletion of Personal Information at any time. If you wish to do so, please follow the instructions provided on the [help page](https://profileengine.com/help)

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

We may revise this Privacy Policy at any time by amending this page. You are expected to check this page from time to time to take notice of any changes we made, as they are binding on you.

**Privity of Contract**

The terms of this Privacy Policy are for the benefit of both Profile Technology Limited and the Directors of Profile Technology Ltd, and are intended to be enforceable by both Profile Technology Limited and the Directors of Profile Technology Ltd.

**Contact**

IMPORTANT: We do not answer messages asking questions which have already been addressed on the [help page](https://profileengine.com/help). Please read the help page in full before contacting us. Communications regarding this Privacy Policy should be sent using the contact form on our [helpdesk site](http://profileengine.deskpro.com/) or by post to: Profile Technology Limited, Suite 4298, 17b Farnham Street, Parnell, Auckland, 1052, New Zealand

. We will endeavour to respond to all queries which are not already answered on the help page within 28 days. If you contact us by post we will not usually respond unless you provide an email address for response.
